Finding Aid for the Reverend Eugene Smathers Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Miscellaneous Series, Boxes Misc. 1-9: Various materials collected by Smathers, arranged by subject. Box Misc. 10: Articles and papers by Smathers, arranged chronologically, 1930-68, plus no dates; Pamphlets by Smathers; publications about Smathers and Big Lick, 1921-68, plus no dates; Board of Na
  - Same (Box Misc. 15, Folder 15)
  - National Child Labor Committee (Box Misc. 15, Folder 16)
  - National Citizens Commission for the Public Schools (Box Misc. 15, Folder 17)
  - Same (Box Misc. 15, Folder 18)
  - National Conference of Christians and Jews (Box Misc. 15, Folder 19)
  - National Congress of Parents and Teachers (Box Misc. 15, Folder 20)
  - National Education Association (Box Misc. 15, Folder 21)
  - National Farmers Union (Box Misc. 15, Folder 22)
  - National Livestock and Meat Board (Box Misc. 15, Folder 23)
  - National Planning Association (Box Misc. 15, Folder 24)
  - National Recreation Association, 1933-1937 (Box Misc. 15, Folder 25)
  - Same, 1938 (Box Misc. 15, Folder 26)
  - Same, 1939 (Box Misc. 15, Folder 27)
  - Same, 1940 (Box Misc. 15, Folder 28)
  - Same n.d.'s (Box Misc. 15, Folder 29)
  - National Religion and Labor Foundation (Box Misc. 15, Folder 30)
  - Nebraska, University of (Box Misc. 15, Folder 31)
  - New Humpehire, University of (Extension Service) (Box Misc. 16, Folder 1)
  - New Jersey State College of Agriculture (Box Misc. 16, Folder 2)
  - Same (Box Misc. 16, Folder 3)
  - Same (Box Misc. 16, Folder 4)
  - New York State College of Agriculture (at Cornell University) (Box Misc. 16, Folder 5)
  - Northern Nut Growers Association (Box Misc. 16, Folder 6)
  - "N" Miscellaneous - Natl. Advisory - Natl. Committee (Box Misc. 16, Folder 7)
  - "H" Misc. - Natl. Conf.- Natl. Home (Box Misc. 16, Folder 8)
  - "N" Misc. - Natl. Industrial - Natl. Student Council (Box Misc. 16, Folder 9)
  - "N" Misc. - Natl. T.B. - N.C. Agricultural Experiment Station (Box Misc. 16, Folder 10)
  - "N" Misc. - N.C. Agricultural Experiment Station - Northern Sts. Cooperative League (Box Misc. 16, Folder 11)
  - Office of Price Administration (Box Misc. 16, Folder 12)
  - Oklahoma Agricultural Experiment Station (Box Misc. 16, Folder 13)
  - "O" Miscellaneous (Box Misc. 16, Folder 14)
  - Pan American Union (Box Misc. 16, Folder 15)
  - Peabody, George College (Box Misc. 16, Folder 16)
  - Presbyterian Church - Bd. of Christian Education, 1924 - 1939 (Box Misc. 16, Folder 17)
  - Same, 1940-1949 (Box Misc. 16, Folder 18)
  - Same, 1949-1951 (Box Misc. 16, Folder 19)
  - Same, 1952-1954 (Box Misc. 16, Folder 20)
  - Same, 1954-1964 (Box Misc. 16, Folder 21)
  - n.d.'s (Box Misc. 16, Folder 22)
  - Same - n.d.'s (Box Misc. 16, Folder 23)
  - Presbyterian Church - Bd. of Foreign Missions (Box Misc. 17, Folder 1)
  - Presbyterian Church - Bd. of National Missions, 1928 - 1942 (Box Misc. 17, Folder 2)
  - Same, 1943 (Box Misc. 17, Folder 3)
  - Presbyterian Church - Bd. of National Missions, 1944 (Box Misc. 17, Folder 4)
  - Same, 1947 (Box Misc. 17, Folder 5)
  - Same, 1949 - 1957 (Box Misc. 17, Folder 6)
  - Same - n.d.'s (Box Misc. 17, Folder 7)
  - Presbyterian Church - General, 1914 - 1929 (Box Misc. 17, Folder 8)
  - Same, 1935 - 1938 (Box Misc. 17, Folder 9)
  - Same, 1942 - 1945 (Box Misc. 17, Folder 10)
  - Same, 1946 - 1951 (Box Misc. 17, Folder 11)
  - Same - 1952 - 1953 (1952/53) (Box Misc. 17, Folder 12)
  - Same, 1952/53 - 1961 (Box Misc. 17, Folder 13)
  - Same, n.d.'s (Box Misc. 17, Folder 15)
  - Presbytery of Cumberland Mtn. (Box Misc. 17, Folder 16)
  - Progreasive Farmer (Box Misc. 17, Folder 17)
  - Public Affairs Pamphlets (Box Misc. 17, Folder 18)
  - "P" Miscellaneous Pa - Ph (Box Misc. 17, Folder 19)
  - "P" Miscellaneous Pi - Purdue Univ. (Box Misc. 17, Folder 20)
  - The Queen's Work (Box Misc. 17, Folder 21)
  - Reader's Digest (Box Misc. 17, Folder 22)
  - Resources for the Futune (Box Misc. 17, Folder 23)
  - Rural Cooperative Community Conference (Box Misc. 17, Folder 24)
  - Rural Life Association (Box Misc. 17, Folder 25)
  - Rural Sociology (Box Misc. 17, Folder 26)
  - "R" Miscellaneous (Box Misc. 17, Folder 27)
  - St. Francis Xavier Extension Dept. (Box Misc. 18, Folder 1)
  - The School of Living (Box Misc. 18, Folder 2)
  - Socialist Party of America (Box Misc. 18, Folder 3)
  - Southeastern Cooperative League (Box Misc. 18, Folder 4)
  - Southern Baptist Convention (Sunday School Publishing Board) (Box Misc. 18, Folder 5)
  - Southern Conference for Human Welfare (Box Misc. 18, Folder 6)
  - Southern Regional Conference (Box Misc. 18, Folder 7)
  - Southern Rural Life Council (Box Misc. 18, Folder 8)
  - South Today (Box Misc. 18, Folder 9)
  - Student League for Industrial Democracy (Box Misc. 18, Folder 10)
  - "S" Miscellaneous - Sa - Social Forces (Box Misc. 18, Folder 11)
  - "S" Misc. - Social Studies - Southern Conf. (Box Misc. 18, Folder 12)
  - "S" Misc. - Southern Pine - Su (Box Misc. 18, Folder 13)
  - Tennessee Farmers Cooperative (Box Misc. 18, Folder 14)
  - Tennessee, State Department of (Institutions and) Public Welfare (Box Misc. 18, Folder 15)
  - Tenn., State of - Misc. (Box Misc. 18, Folder 16)
  - Tenn,. Univ. of - Agricultural Experiment Station, 1918 - 1941 (Box Misc. 18, Folder 17)
  - Same, 1941 - 1953 (Box Misc. 18, Folder 18)
  - Tennessee, Univ. of - Agricultural Extension Service - Publications, 1921-36 (Box Misc. 18, Folder 19)
  - Same, 1937 - April, 1939 (Box Misc. 18, Folder 20)
  - Same, May, 1939 - 1941 (Box Misc. 18, Folder 21)
  - Same, 1942 - 1965 (Box Misc. 18, Folder 22)
  - Tennessee Valley Authority (Box Misc. 18, Folder 23)
  - Texas Agricultural Experiment Station (Box Misc. 18, Folder 24)
  - Tuskegee Institute (Box Misc. 18, Folder 25)
  - "T" Miscellaneous (Box Misc. 18, Folder 26)
  - United Christian Missionary Society (Box Misc. 18, Folder 27)
  - United Christian Youth Movement (Box Misc. 18, Folder 28)
  - United Presbyterian Church, 1958 (Box Misc. 18, Folder 29)
  - United Presbyterian Church, 1959 (Box Misc. 18, Folder 30)
  - United Presbyterian Church, 1960-61 (Box Misc. 18, Folder 31)
  - United Presbyterian Church, 1961-62 (Box Misc. 18, Folder 32)
  - United Presbyterian Church, 1963 (Box Misc. 18, Folder 33)
  - United Presbyterian Church, 1964 (Box Misc. 18, Folder 34)
  - United Presbyterian Church, 1965-66 (Box Misc. 19, Folder 1)
  - Same, 1967 (Box Misc. 19, Folder 2)
  - Same, 1967 (Box Misc. 19, Folder 3)
  - Same, 1967 (Box Misc. 19, Folder 4)
  - Same, 1967 (Box Misc. 19, Folder 5)
  - Same, 1968 and n.d.'s (Box Misc. 19, Folder 6)
  - U.S. Advisory Committee on Education, 1938 (Box Misc. 19, Folder 7)
  - U.S. Advisory Committee on Education, 1938 - 1939 (Box Misc. 19, Folder 8)
  - U.S. Dept. of Agriculture - Bureau of Agricultural Economics, 1935 - 38 (Box Misc. 19, Folder 9)
  - Same, 1939-40 (Box Misc. 19, Folder 10)
  - Same, 1940 (Box Misc. 19, Folder 11)
  - Same, April, 1941 - Oct., 1941 (Box Misc. 19, Folder 12)
  - Same, Nov., 1941 (Box Misc. 19, Folder 13)
  - Same, Jan., 1942 - March, 1942 (Box Misc. 19, Folder 14)
  - Same, April, 1942 (Box Misc. 19, Folder 15)
  - Same, August, 1952 - Dec., 1942 (Box Misc. 19, Folder 16)
  - Same - 1942 general (i.e. no particular aonth of publication given) (Box Misc. 19, Folder 17)
  - Same, 1943 - Sept. 1944 (Box Misc. 19, Folder 18)
  - Same, Sept., 1944 - Nov., 1944 (Box Misc. 19, Folder 19)
  - Same, 1945 (Box Misc. 19, Folder 20)
  - U.S.D.A. - Bureau of Agricultural Economics, 1946 (Box Misc. 20, Folder 1)
  - Same - 1947, and n.d.'s (Box Misc. 20, Folder 2)
  - U.S.N.A. - Dept. Circulars (Box Misc. 20, Folder 3)
  - U.S.D.A. - Extension Service, 1932-35 (Box Misc. 20, Folder 4)
  - Same, 1936 (Box Misc. 20, Folder 5)
  - Same, 1936-65 (Box Misc. 20, Folder 6)
  - U.S.D.A. - Farm Credit Administration, 1935-39 (Box Misc. 20, Folder 7)
  - U.S.D.A. - Farm Credit Administration, 1939 (Box Misc. 20, Folder 8)
  - Same, 1940-48 (Box Misc. 20, Folder 9)
  - Same, 1948-51 (Box Misc. 20, Folder 10)
  - Same - 1951-54 and n.d.'s (Box Misc. 20, Folder 11)
  - U.S.D.A.- Farmer Cooperative Service (Box Misc. 20, Folder 12)
  - U.S.D.A.- Farmer's Bulletin, 1915 - 26 (Box Misc. 20, Folder 13)
  - Same, 1929-34 (Box Misc. 20, Folder 14)
  - Same, 1936-37 (Box Misc. 20, Folder 15)
  - Same, 1938 (Box Misc. 20, Folder 16)
  - Same - 1939-44 and n.d.'s (Box Misc. 20, Folder 17)
  - U.S.D.A.- Fara Security Administration, 1938-40 (Box Misc. 20, Folder 18)
  - Same, 1940-45 (Box Misc. 20, Folder 19)
  - U.S.D.A. - Forest Service, 1938-39 (Box Misc. 20, Folder 20)
  - Same, 1940 (Box Misc. 20, Folder 21)
  - Same 1943-50 and n.d.'s (Box Misc. 20, Folder 22)
  - U.S.D.A. - Interbureau Committee on Postwar Problems (Box Misc. 20, Folder 23)
  - U.S.D.A.- Leaflets (Box Misc. 20, Folder 24)
  - U.S.D.A. - Miscellaneous Publications, 1938-48 (Box Misc. 20, Folder 25)
  - U.S.D.A. - Miscellaneous Publications, 1935-37 (Box Misc. 21, Folder 1)
  - U.S.D.A.- Rural Electirfication Administration (Box Misc. 21, Folder 2)
  - U.S.D.A. - Soil Conservation Service, 1938-40 (Box Misc. 21, Folder 3)
  - U.S.D.A. - Soil Conservation Service 1941-46 and n.d.'s (Box Misc. 21, Folder 4)
  - U.S.D.A. - STATISTICAL BULLETIN (Box Misc. 21, Folder 5)
  - U.S.D.A. - Technical Bulletin (Box Misc. 21, Folder 6)
  - U.S.D.A. - Miscellaneous, 1914-40 (Box Misc. 21, Folder 7)
  - Same, 1941-43 (Box Misc. 21, Folder 8)
  - Same 1943-65 and n.d.'s (Box Misc. 21, Folder 9)
  - U.S. Dept. of Commerce (Box Misc. 21, Folder 10)
  - U.S. Dept. of Health, Education and Welfare (Box Misc. 21, Folder 11)
  - U.S. Dept of the Interior (Box Misc. 21, Folder 12)
  - U.S. Dept of Justice, Oct., 1946 (Box Misc. 21, Folder 13)
  - U.S. Dept of Justice, Nov., 1946 (Box Misc. 21, Folder 14)
  - U.S. Dept of Justice, Nov., 1946 (Box Misc. 21, Folder 15)
  - U.S. Dept. of Justice, Nov., 1946 (Box Misc. 21, Folder 16)
  - Same n.d.'s (Box Misc. 21, Folder 17)
  - U.S. Dept. of Labor (Box Misc. 21, Folder 18)
  - U.S. Dept of State (Box Misc. 21, Folder 19)
  - U.S. Federal Seeurity Agency (Box Misc. 21, Folder 20)
  - U.S. House of Representatives (Box Misc. 21, Folder 21)
  - U.S. Office of War Information (Box Misc. 21, Folder 22)
  - U.S. Senate (Box Misc. 21, Folder 23)
  - U.S. Social Security Board (Box Misc. 21, Folder 24)
  - U.S. Works Progress Administration (Box Misc. 21, Folder 25)
  - U.S.G.P.O. Miscellaneous (Box Misc. 21, Folder 26)
  - Same (Box Misc. 21, Folder 27)
  - Utah Works Progress Administration (Box Misc. 21, Folder 1)
  - "U" Miscellaneous (Box Misc. 21, Folder 2)
  - Vanderbilt University (Box Misc. 21, Folder 3)
  - Virginia Polytechnic University (Box Misc. 21, Folder 4)
  - Virginia, Univ. of (Extension Senice) (Box Misc. 21, Folder 5)
  - "V" Miscellaneous (Box Misc. 21, Folder 6)
  - Western Piae Association (Box Misc. 21, Folder 7)
  - Westminister Press (Box Misc. 21, Folder 8)
  - Wisconsin, Univ. of (Box Misc. 21, Folder 9)
  - Wisconsin Miscellaneous (Box Misc. 21, Folder 10)
  - Woman's Home Companion (Box Misc. 21, Folder 11)
  - World Council of Churches (Box Misc. 21, Folder 12)
  - "W" Misc. Warner - Works (Box Misc. 21, Folder 13)
  - "W" Misc. World Horizons - Wyker (Box Misc. 21, Folder 14)
  - "Z" Misc. (Box Misc. 21, Folder 15)
  - Pamphlet Fragments and no publishers (Box Misc. 21, Folder 16)
    (Also in Box #22 are two photographs, Blue Ridge Staff, 1928, and Presbyterian Theological Seminary Faculty and Class, 1932, Louisville, Ky.)